welcome back to another shotcut video
欢迎回到另一个截图视频
editing tutorial in this video we're
编辑教程在这段视频中我们
going to talk about the keyframes
接下来我们来谈谈关键帧
feature so adding keyframes this is
功能 因此添加关键帧
getting starting to touch on maybe
开始接触也许
animation or making things change
动漫或让事情发生变化
effects and filters at different points
不同点的效果和滤镜
of the video so to get started we're
所以为了开始 我们将
gonna drag in this video clip to our
我要把这段视频片段拖到我们的
timeline and some different filters have
时间线和一些不同的过滤器具有
can be keyframe than some canned in the
可以是关键帧而不是一些罐头中的
last video we talked a little bit about
我们谈到的最后一段视频
text so when we add text on like if we
文本 所以当我们添加文本时 如果我们
add text we click on video go down to
添加我们点击的文本视频转到
text so we have our different text here
文本 所以我们这里有不同的文本
you say my text so this has some options
你说我的文本 所以这有一些选项
for one click on keyframe it has some
只需在关键帧上点击一下 它就会有一些
options for when it first appears if we
第一次出现时的选项 如果我们
that's this green start so if we play
这就是绿色开始 所以如果我们打
our video here it won't appear until it
我们的视频在这之前不会出现
gets to that point in time and if we
到了那个时间点 如果我们
want to go to the end of this and have
想要走到这一步的最后
it only be on for a short amount of time
它只上映了很短的时间
we just bring it to here so this is all
我们只是把它带到这里 所以这就是全部
happening on this keyframes tab not on
在此关键帧选项卡上发生 而不是在
the timeline tab if you're wondering
如果您想知道时间表选项卡
where that green and start end is if we
绿色和起点是哪里 如果我们
come here to the end it just shortens
走到尽头吧 它只是变短了
the length of the video
视频的长度
so under keyframes is where we get to
因此 在关键帧下 我们可以看到
this red and green with these little
这个红绿相间的小东西
black circles but this will put the text
黑色圆圈 但这将把文本
on the video just for a short time and
在视频上只有很短的一段时间
then again it goes off and if we're
然后它又一次爆炸 如果我们
doing if we zoom in here if we have any
如果我们放大这里 如果我们有
effects to this this is where it kind of
对这个的影响这就是它
changes maybe the position so this is
可能会改变位置 所以这是
actually right now it's the same because
实际上现在是一样的 因为
nothing has changed but we could do it
一切都没有改变 但我们可以做到
so by this point one thing we could do
所以在这一点上我们可以做一件事
is change the color so if we change the
就是改变颜色 所以如果我们改变
color and go to red it's going to be red
颜色变成红色就会变成红色
at this point but since we didn't change
在这一点上但因为我们没有改变
it at the beginning maybe that part is
它在开始的时候可能那部分是
not keyframe well oh it's not so the
不是关键帧哦 不是这样的
text color I guess is not keyframe level
我猜文本颜色不是关键帧级别
unfortunately and the reason we can tell
不幸的是 我们之所以能说出
that is there's no icon right here to
也就是说 这里没有图标
the side of it that says it's keyframe
它的一侧显示它是关键帧
of all so the only thing that's key
所以唯一关键的是
frame of all of this text is the
所有这篇文章的框架是
position of it and the size isn't the
它的位置和大小不是
where it's at the justification isn't
它在正当性的地方不是
the text itself isn't just the position
文本本身不仅仅是位置
is
是
and if we hover over that says use
如果我们将鼠标悬停在上面 说明使用
keyframes for this parameter so that
此参数的关键帧 以便
just tells us that it's able to be
只是告诉我们 它有能力
keyframe Abul so what we could do now is
关键帧ABUL所以我们现在可以做的是
move this up to like here and what that
把这个移到像这里和那里一样的位置
will do is it'll start down here it'll
它会从这里开始 它会
appear and then it'll move but it's not
出现了 然后它就会移动 但它不是
working properly it move the text box if
正常工作时 它会移动文本框
it's not moving the text super-annoying
它不会移动文本-超级烦人
but at least we're learning what's
但至少我们学到了
happening it has sort of let's get rid
发生了这样的事情 让我们摆脱它
of this one altogether because a better
因为一个更好的
example is if we do maybe let's do
例如 如果我们这样做了 也许我们可以
another effect like blur
另一种效果 如模糊
I think blur was keyframe Abul yeah so
我认为模糊是关键 是啊 所以
we see it has this little icon to the
我们看到它有一个小图标
side of it use keyframes so we couldn't
它的一侧使用关键帧 所以我们不能
click this we're gonna do that in a
点击这个 我们将在一个
second but for now we can just go to the
第二个 但现在我们可以去
keyframes on it and we can just use this
关键帧在上面 我们可以用这个
little slide out so it's going to start
稍微滑出一点 这样它就会开始
with these settings and by the time we
有了这些设置 当我们
get to here we can change these settings
转到此处 我们可以更改这些设置
we can make it really blurry let's do
我们可以让它变得非常模糊 让我们做
this so that should adjust and start out
这样就应该调整并开始
not very blurry and then gradually get
不是很模糊 然后逐渐变得
blurry we probably do it the other way
模糊我们可能会用另一种方式
around
在附近
so it gets more and more blurry then it
所以它变得越来越模糊 然后它
just stays blurry so if we wanted to do
只是保持模糊 所以如果我们想要
that other way around we just reset this
换句话说 我们只是重置了这个
to how it was we go to the beginning and
我们从一开始就开始了
then we make it more blurry to start
然后我们让它开始变得更模糊
with now it'll come into focus as we
现在它将成为焦点 因为我们
play so that's just using the basic
播放 所以这只是使用基本的
rudimentary this doesn't really it
初级的这并不是真的
really gives us two keyframes one at the
实际上提供了两个关键帧 其中一个位于
beginning and then one word for this
开始 然后用一个词表示这个
circle is it's a really it's kind of an
圆圈是它真的它是一种
easy user-friendly way to do it but it
一种简单、用户友好的方式 但它
doesn't give us a lot of control because
不会给我们很大的控制权 因为
there's only two keyframes the keyframe
只有两个关键帧关键帧
means we can't change anything in
意味着我们不能更改任何内容
between here we can't adjust and change
在这里 我们不能调整和改变
the blurriness right here we can only
就在这里的模糊 我们只能
change it right at this point of the
将其更改为正确的位置
circle or at the very beginning of the
圆圈或在开始处
clip okay I've loaded in a new video
好的 我已经加载了一段新视频
clip I'm gonna show you the more
我要给你看更多的片段
advanced way of doing keyframes in shot
在快照中制作关键帧的高级方法
cut I don't have any filters applied to
停我没有应用任何滤镜
this right now but while it selected
这是现在 但当它选择
we'll apply a filter we could do the
我们将应用一个过滤器 我们可以
blur again but really any filter that
再次模糊 但实际上任何滤镜
has this keyframe icon this little icon
有这个关键帧图标这个小图标
that says use keyframes for this
这就是说使用关键帧进行此操作
parameter this tells us that
参数告诉我们
we can use these so what this does is
我们可以使用这些 这样做的目的是
it'll actually change the coloring of
它实际上会改变颜色
the clip here and so we can click down
剪辑在这里 这样我们就可以点击
here and all of a sudden that creates
在这里 突然之间 这创造了
this mid-tones gamma which matches this
这个与此匹配的中间色调伽马
and we see this as highlighted in blue
我们看到这个以蓝色突出显示
so now any changes we make here will be
所以现在我们在这里做的任何改变都将是
applied to this clip and it put a little
应用到这个剪辑上 它放了一点
dot at the point we were at whenever
无论何时何地 在我们所在的点上都是点
when we click that so if we come to a
当我们点击它时 如果我们到达一个
new point while we're here on the
当我们在这里的时候 新的观点
keyframes and we can make an adjustment
关键帧 我们可以进行调整
to this so now we make it sort of this
所以现在我们把它做成这样
red well we see down here well let's
红色的 好的 我们在下面看到 好的 让我们
make it blue just so we're not confused
把它改成蓝色 这样我们就不会困惑了
there's this little red node this is a
这是一个红色的小节点 这是一个
keyframe at this point there's another
关键帧在这一点上还有另一个
keyframe at the beginning so we see
开头的关键帧 因此我们可以看到
there's two so this is essentially what
有两个 所以这基本上就是
we were doing last time where it's gonna
我们上一次做的是
it's gonna fade it's gonna slowly apply
它会慢慢褪色它会慢慢起作用
we see that's happening so you look up
我们看到这正在发生 所以你抬头看
here on the actual color wheel we see
在实际的色轮上我们可以看到
that dot just moving by itself and then
那个圆点自己移动 然后
it gets that point it'll just stop if we
它达到了这一点 它就会停止 如果我们
want it to go to a different color we
我想让它变成不同的颜色
can come to whatever point we want and
可以达到我们想要的任何程度
we can move it down to maybe like this
我们可以把它移到像这样的地方
green and now it's gonna fade to that so
绿色 现在它将会褪色 所以
it'll fade to this color then it will
它会褪色到这个颜色 然后它会
fade over to this more green and it just
消失到更绿的地方 它就这样
stays at that last one and if we wanted
住在最后一家 如果我们想
to go back to how it was originally we
回到我们最初的样子
just move it back to the middle and now
只要把它移回中间 现在
we have this so we have these different
我们有这个 所以我们有这些不同的
key frames we've now set for keyframes
我们现在已经为关键帧设置了关键帧
just for the mid-tones so all it's doing
只是为了中间色调 所以它所做的
is doing the mid-tones maybe we want to
正在做中间色调也许我们想要
add in another one we can click this one
添加另一个 我们可以点击这个
here this highlights and that'll create
在这里突出显示 这将创建
let's not do the highlights let's click
我们不要做重点了 让我们点击
it click yes so we won't do that one
它单击是 因此我们不会执行该操作
instead let's do a different let's do
相反 让我们做一个不同的 让我们做
well we can do I guess we'll do the blur
好吧 我们可以做 我想我们会做侠影
since we had that one up before because
因为我们以前有过那个 因为
the blur has two different ones as well
侠影也有两个不同的版本
width and height so under blur we can
宽度和高度 所以在模糊下我们可以
add a keyframe in starting right here
从此处开始在中添加关键帧
and they'll show us the width and then
他们会给我们展示宽度 然后
we can come again to here and make an
我们可以再来这里 做一个
adjustment to that oh this one there we
调整到那个哦 这一个我们在那里
go so now we have it blurred there and
去吧 现在我们把它弄模糊了
then we come back down to this point and
然后我们回到这一点
go reset
转到重置
so now it's going to blur but it's also
所以现在它会变得模糊 但它也
still applying those colors
仍在使用这些颜色
it gets really blurry up at this point
在这一点上 它变得非常模糊
here then it goes back down to be not
在这里 然后它又回到了不是
blurred and back to the normal colors so
模糊了 又回到了正常的颜色
we have two different filters applied
我们应用了两种不同的过滤器
but we need to click on them to see so
但我们需要点击它们才能看到
listen has chose the mid-tones this one
Listen选择了这首歌的中间色调
shows the blur but there are each on
显示了模糊 但每一个都在
their own and so unless it's selected
他们自己的 所以除非它被选中
we're not gonna see which one there is
我们不会看到有哪一个
that makes sense but I guess we could do
这是有道理的 但我想我们可以
this one so we could up these ones we
这个 所以我们可以把这些放上去
can apply and have three different ones
可以申请并拥有三种不同的
as long as it's on the same filter when
只要它在同一过滤器上 当
we go to a new filter it doesn't show so
我们转到一个新的过滤器 它没有显示出来
we can't see width on the same keyframes
我们在相同的关键帧上看不到宽度
tab I guess you could say as these
我想你可以这样说
different colors but we can color these
不同的颜色 但我们可以给这些上色
and add these and they're gonna be all
再加上这些 它们就会变成
their own separate ones and so we get
他们各自独立的 所以我们得到了
all these different kinds of adjustments
所有这些不同类型的调整
happening here and then we just see some
发生在这里 然后我们只是看到一些
craziness going on with coloring and
疯狂地涂色和涂色
also with a second it should blur here
还有一秒钟 它应该在这里变得模糊
as we go in to blur that makes sense
当我们进入模糊的时候 这是有意义的
what's going on if you've never used
如果你从来没有用过
keyframes before it can be confusing if
之前的关键帧可能会令人困惑 如果
you have used keyframes you should be
您已经使用了您应该使用的关键帧
pretty familiar with what's going on
对正在发生的事情非常熟悉
here these ones are just setting since
在这里 这些是刚刚设置的 因为
there's so many data points these things
有太多的数据点这些东西
are just setting the actual point
只是设定了实际的时间点
whereas this one is actually showing the
而这个实际上显示的是
level so we can instead of clicking up
级别 这样我们就可以不再点击向上
here under width we can actually click
在这里的宽度下 我们可以实际点击
the node now and we can take that blur
现在这个节点 我们可以把那个模糊
up or down so this this line is
向上或向下所以这条线是
representing the intensity whereas the
表示强度 而
other one wasn't we can do the height on
另一个不是我们可以做的高度
this one too so if we add in height and
这个也是如此 如果我们加上高度和
we go to this point and just make some
我们到了这一点 只是制作了一些
sort of a change and then come here so
有点变化 然后就这样来到这里
now we're adding in a few different
现在我们加入了几个不同的
things so now we have to we're adjusting
所以现在我们必须我们正在调整
this height and this width if you watch
这个高度和这个宽度如果你看的话
these bars as I play these bars are
当我演奏这些小节的时候 这些小节是
slowly changing you know back and forth
慢慢地改变你知道的来回
to do some interesting types of things
做一些有趣的事情
so any filter that you find any filter
所以你找到的任何过滤器
at all that has the audio so we have
它有音频 所以我们有
this gain and volume is keyframe Abul so
这个增益和体积是关键帧abu so
we could we could apply an adjustment to
我们可以对其进行调整
the volume and have it be a different
卷 并让它成为一个不同的
volume level at
音量级别为
point then another point we can apply a
点 然后我们可以应用另一个点
lot of these a lot of the different
很多这些都有很多不同
effects just look at to see if they have
效果只需看看它们是否有
it so sharpen is going to have it most
它如此锐利 将拥有最多的
of the effects are going to have these
会产生这样的影响
icons so play around with those
图标 所以玩玩这些图标
hopefully you found this video
希望你找到了这段视频
informative really experienced and just
见多识广 经验丰富 公正
playing and seeing what happens when you
玩一玩 看一看当你
apply different keyframes and changing
应用不同的关键帧和更改
them is what's really gonna help you
它们才是真正能帮助你的东西
learn how they work and so play with
了解它们是如何工作的 并因此玩耍
that go and leave your questions and
把你的问题留下来
comments below and I'll catch you in the
在下面发表评论 我会在
next video
下一个视频